Neil V. Rosenberg bluegrass music collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Sound recordings, Digital files are located in afc2002009_dc001. Please see the AFC reference staff for access.
  - Old Dominion Barn Dance; Grand Ole Opry dubs 1940s-early 1950s; Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys singles; Columbia test pressings, 1940s-early 1950s, AFC 2002/009: SR194; RXI 0171; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:47:11, Side 2: 00:47:04): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - Old Dominion Barn Dance, undated
        - "Are You Coming Back To Me"
          Duet with Buck Graves
      - Grand Ole Opry dubs [group 1], circa 1940s-early 1950s
        - "Christmas Time Is Coming"
        - "Don't Blame It All On Me"
        - "Bluebird Singing In The Blue Ridge Mountains"
        - "I Still Write Your Name In The Sand"
        - "Wake Up Susan"
        - "Have You Come To Say Goodbye"
        - "God Loves His Children"
        - "Down The Road"
        - "Earl's Breakdown"
      - Grand Ole Opry dubs [group 2], circa 1940s-early 1950s
        - "Foggy Mountain Special"
        - "Till The End Of The World Rolls Around"
        - "Hand In Hand With Jesus"
        - "Salty Dog Blues"
      - Grand Ole Opry dubs [group 3], circa 1940s-early 1950s
        - "Little Tom"
          Ferlin Husky
        - "Thou Shalt Not Steal"
          Kitty Wells
        - "Turkey In The Straw"
        - "Love And Wealth"
      - Columbia test pressings: Bill Monroe
        - "Nobody Loves Me," circa 1945
          C 4357
    - Side 2
      - Columbia test pressings: Bill Monroe
        - "Come Back To Me In My Dreams," circa 1945
          C 4361
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys
        - "Shake My Mother's Hand For Me," 1942
          BB 8953
        - "Were You There," 1942
        - "Crying Holy Unto The Lord," 1941
          BB 8611
      - Curly Parker and Peewee Lambert radio programs, Ohio, circa 1952, Curly Parker
        - "Crying Holy Unto The Lord"
        - "Salty Dog Blues"
        - "Rawhide"
        - "Nine Pound Hammer"
        - "Blue Grass Stomp"
        - "Salty Dog Blues"
        - "The Wandering Boy"
      - The Greenhorns
        - "Zatracenej život," 1967
          The title translates as "Before I Met You." Supraphon O 43 0354 (Czechoslovakian release).
        - "Abilene," 1967
          Supraphon O 43 0354 (Czechoslovakian release).
      - Fake Mountain Boys
        - Gärdebylåten
          Swedish release
      - Tennessee Travelers
        From Sweden. Haglund brothers (Urban and Mats) made up the Tennessee Travelers. When their brother Thomas joined the group they were the Midnight Cowboys. Rosenberg identifies the group as the Tennessee Travelers. Personnel: Urban, guitar; Mats, banjo; Thomas, fiddle; and another unidentified musician dubbed in.
        - "John Hardy"
        - "Foggy Mountain Breakdown"
        - "Foggy Mountain Special"
        - "Buck Dancer's Choice"
        - "Turkey In The Straw"
        - "Saturday Night Shuffle"
        - "Devil's Dream"
          Excerpt
  - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys at Bean Blossom; recorded at Jim Peva's home, AFC 2002/009: SR195; Jim Peva; RXI 0226; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:47:56, Side 2: 00:48:12): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at the afternoon show, Brown County Jamboree, Bean Blossom, Indiana. Personnel: James W. Monroe, guitar; Rual Yarborough, banjo; Kenny Baker, fiddle; Norm Carlson, string bass. The recording was made by Jim Peva.
    - Side 1
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, April 20, 1969
        - Introduction by Silver Spurs Ragsdale
        - "Watermelon Hanging On The Vine" (theme)
        - "Sally Goodin"
        - "I Washed My Hands In The Muddy Water"
        - "I Haven't Seen Mary For Years"
        - "Bluegrass Breakdown"
        - "Molly And Tenbrooks"
        - talks about change in repertoire
        - "Footprints In The Snow"
        - talks about audience response on the Grand Ole Opry
        - "Muleskinner Blues"
        - talk about Red and Fred
        - "Blue Moon Of Kentucky"
          Singalong
        - "Working On A Building"
        - "Down In The Willow Garden"
          Talks about drinking in public
        - "Uncle Pen"
        - memorat [sic]; father drinking; whiskey to horses
        - "Raw Hide"
    - Side 2
      - Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys, April 20, 1969
        - "Florida Blues"
          Birch Monroe, fiddle; he makes a dedication
        - "Durang's Hornpipe"
          Birch Monroe, fiddle; Bill dances
        - "Life's Railway To Heaven"
        - "A Beautiful Life"
        - Monroe's pitch for Blue Grass Festival; Neil Rosenberg and Roger Smith introduced
        - "Orange Blossom Special"
          Roger Smith featured on the fiddle
        - "Salt Creek"
          Neil Rosenberg featured on the banjo
        - Red Rector introduced; twins
        - "Old Joe Clark"
          On banjo and fiddle
        - "Lonesome Road Blues"
          Rual Yarborough, fiddles, mandolin; Neil Rosenberg, fiddles, mandolins; Rual Yarborough
        - "Once A Day"
          By Cleata Carr
        - "Goodbye Old Pal"
        - "Y'all Come"
      - Bill Monroe, mandolin; Roland White, guitar; Kenny Baker, fiddle, December 14, 1968
        Recorded at Jim Peva's home, Plainfield, Indiana
        - unidentified song
        - "A Beautiful Life"
          Vic Jordan, lead vocal; Jim Peva, bass vocal
        - "Big Sandy River"
  - Earl Taylor interview by Scott Hambly, March 30, 1969, AFC 2002/009: SR196; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 00:31:58, Side 2: 00:28:23): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Recorded at 1401 Walnut Street, Apt. 3, Santa Ana, California.
  - Indiana University Folksong Club record project, May 1965, AFC 2002/009: SR197; RXI 0172; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:48:16, Side 2: 00:29:21): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    Dub copy of the master recordings in the Archives of Traditional Music, Indiana University, Bloomington. From Don Sheets's studio, Nashville, Tennessee.
    - Side 1
      - Reel 1
        - Tom Foreman
          - "He Was A Friend Of Mine"
          - "Venezuela"
            Two takes
      - Reel 2
        - Tom Foreman
          - "Mirror, Mirror On The Wall" - Tom Foreman
          - "The Handsome Cabin Boy" - Tom Foreman
        - Susie Rider
          - "How Long"
            Second guitar may be played by Pete Hoover
          - "Muddy Water Blues"
            Pete Aceves, harp
          - "Little Maggie"
      - Reel 3
        - Pigeon Hill Ramblers
          Personnel: Dave Satterfield, guitar; Bernella Satterfield (Nell Levin), fiddle; Neil Rosenberg, banjo; Ann Rosenberg, string bass; Dan Scullin, mandolin
          - "Leavin' Tennessee"
            Dave, lead; Bernella, tenor
          - "Arthritis Blues"
          - "Today Has Been A Lonesome Day"
            Dave, lead vocal/tenor chorus; Neil, lead chorus
          - "Little Birdie"
            Dave, lead; Ann, tenor; Neil, bass
      - Reel 4
        - Greg Hildebrand
          - "Farm Song (Down On My Farm)"
          - "No More Reds In The Union"
          - "Cocaine"
    - Side 2
      - Reel 4, continued
        - Greg Hildebrand
          - "Song Of My Hands"
        - Hootchie Kootchie Jug Busters
          - instrumental
          - "You're Some Ugly Child"
          - "Rampart Street"
      - Reel 5
        - Hootchie Kootchie Jug Busters
          - "Rampart Street"
          - "Ace In The Hole"
          - "2:19"
          - "Brownsville"
        - Aceves and Levin (Pete Aceves and Eric Levin)
        - "Baby Please Don't Go"
        - "Low Down And Dirty (That's Alright, Mama)"
        - Reel 6
        - Aceves and Levin (Pete Aceves and Eric Levin)
          - "Skin Game"
          - "Floating Bridge"
  - Grand Ole Opry dubs, AFC 2002/009: SR198; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 00:06:18, Side 2: 00:06:25): analog, 7 1/2 ips and 15 ips, half track, mono; 5 in.
    - Side 1
      - Monroe with Don Lineberger, banjo, March 6, 1965
        - "Lonesome Wind Blues"
        - "Were You There"
        - Doug Edson counting to 20
    - Side 2
      - Flatt and Scruggs, March 6, 1965
        - Martha White theme
        - "I Still Miss Someone"
          Following this song, the tape is blank to the end of the reel.
  - Byron Berline and Neil V. Rosenberg at the Fiddlers Festival, Richland Hills, Texas, August 17, 1968, AFC 2002/009: SR199
    - Sound recording, RXI 0173; 1 sound tape reel (00:13:22): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      According to Rosenberg, Hank Schmidt may have put this tape together "from two original reels with the introduction coming at the end of one tape and the music at the start of another" (email from Rosenberg to Brian Miksis, March 7, 2012).
      - "Sally Johnson"
      - "Sally Goodin'"
      - "Lonesome Creek Blues"
      - "Salt Creek"
      - "Soldier's Joy"
      - "Sally Johnson" (introduction)
    - Documentation
      - Song list and production notes for SR199, February 4, 2012, nvr1968-08-17 NVR and Berline.txt; 1 manuscript; black and white, digital (.txt)
  - John Morris shows with Jimmy Martin interviews; Jimmy Martin/John Morris radio ID plugs, AFC 2002/009: SR200; Chuck Crawford; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 01:03:05, Side 2: 00:31:33): analog, 3 3/4 and 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
    - Side 1
      - John Morris, "Gospel Time," undated
        John Morris, "Gospel Time" radio show from an Ypsilanti, Michigan, radio station. Complete with station calls. According to Rosenberg the original notes say April 1968 but 1969 is a more likely date.
        - "There's A Mother Waiting For You," undated
          Maybelle Carter
        - "This World Is Not My Home," undated
          Jimmy Martin
        - "My Lord Keeps A Record," undated
          Carl Story
        - "Shine, Hallelujah, Shine," undated
        - "A Better Place To Go," undated
          The Cook Duet
        - Interview with Jimmy Martin, probably 1968 or 1969
          His early history, Tex Clymer, radio shows in the 1930s and 1940s, Cas Walker, joining Monroe, going to the Opry (getting up nerve)Monroe fires Mac Wiseman and hires Jimmy Martin. King recordings with Bobby Osborne, Detroit job, three years, from King to Victor, Sid Nathan, what happened to Victor's bluegrass, Flatt and Columbia, the record business.
        - "Precious Memories," 1939
          Wade Mainer
        - "I'm Traveling On And On," undated
        - "Light At The River," undated
        - "Shut-In's Prayer," undated
        - "Gospel Ship," undated
          Monroe Brothers
      - Station ID - different date, Morris show
        - "What Would You Give (In Exchange)," undated
          Wade Mainer and and Zeke Morris
        - "Silver Haired Daddy Of Mine," undated
          Gene Autry and Jimmy Long
    - Side 2
      - A series of Jimmy Martin/John Morris radio ID plugs, undated
      - Interview with Jimmy Martin for the Ralph Stanley Tape Club, April 27, 1969
        - "Best Of Love" - first Decca gospel cut with Monroe, and "Poison Love," "Uncle Pen," "Golden Leaves.. ."
        - Osbornes; King Brothers; gives personnel
        - Working in Detroit - drew mail; sales
        - Lists "biggest" records
        - Winning radio contest - bluegrass not played by d.j. [disc jockey]
        - Talk about new d.j.'s
        - "Watering down" bluegrass
        - No bluegrass into colleges until "Hootenanny" TV show started
        - Pianos used in bluegrass - could be done
        - Drums used in bluegrass - rhythm necessary
        - Upcoming recording plans
        - Talk about recording company, Decca
        - Working with Bill Monroe
        - Bluegrass festivals
        - His band: Bill Yates, string bass; Chris Warner, banjo; Vernon Derrick, fiddle and mandolin; Gloria Belle, girl singer
        - He recorded on the Shenandoah Valley Trio Columbia cuts
          End of the interview. Further broadcast material listed PTO.
      - John Morris, "Gospel Time," Fathers Day, 1969
        Radio show from Ypsilanti, Michigan, radio station
        - "Sunny Side Of Life"
          Blue Sky Boys
        - "It's Because God Planned It That Way"
          Red Smiley
        - "Daddy And Home"
          Jimmie Rodgers
        - "I'm Going To Write To Heaven For I Know My Daddy's There"
  - Grisman/Keith/Rose demo; excerpts from two interviews of Bill Monroe by Ralph Rinzler; Wakefield and Grisman; The Country All-Stars; Flatt and Scruggs at Iron City, AFC 2002/009: SR201; Sandy Rothman; 1 sound tape reel (Side 1: 01:37:55, Side 2: 00:36:32): analog, quarter track, 3 3/4 ips; 7 in.
    Left track only at some points. The tape was received from Sandy Rothman on October 4, 1972.
    - Side 1
      - Grisman/Keith/Rose demo, 1964-1965
        Dub of a rehearsal tape made for Clarence White in anticipation of an Elektra [record company] LP which never came off. Personnel: Dave Grisman, mandolin; Bill Keith, banjo; Artie Rose, guitar.
        - "Little Sadie"
        - "Opus 57 In G Minor"
        - B flat tune
        - "Out Of Joint"
        - "Nola"
        - E major modal
        - "Fanny Hill"
        - "Caravan"
        - "Sally In The Garden"
      - Excerpts from two interviews of Bill Monroe by Ralph Rinzler
        - Interview 1, circa 1964-1965
          Recorded in Cambridge, Massachusetts. Jim Rooney and David Grisman present.
        - Interview 2, 1963
          Recorded at the Chicago Folk Festival. About rhythm; Dave Macon stories; the Ozark people; tent show story.
      - Wakefield and Grisman, 1964
        Frank Wakefield, mandolin; Dave Grisman, guitar.
        - "Orange Blossom Mandolin"
        - untitle piece in G
      - The Country All-Stars, 1952-1953
        Recorded on the Victor record label. Personnel: Chet Atkins; Homer and Jethro; Bud Isaacs, steel guitar; Dale Potter, fiddle; C. Grean, string bass
        - "Marie"
        - "Whats The Reason"
          The Campbell Coe theme song.
        - "Sweet Georgia Brown"
        - "Fiddle Sticks"
        - "Fiddle Patch"
      - Cowboy Copas
        - "Roly Poly," 1952-1953
      - Flatt and Scruggs at Iron City, April 7, 1961
        Recorded at Iron City, Tennessee
        - Intros
        - "Florida Blues"
          Possibly "Durham's Reel"
        - "I Know What It Means To Be Lonesome"
        - advertisements for M & W coupons and Pet Milk
        - "Maggie"
          Josh
        - "Polka On The Banjo"
        - "Groundspeed"
        - "Nobody's Business"
        - "Foggy Mountain Special"
        - break
        - "That Was Before I Met You"
          Solos only
        - "Darling Pal Of Mine"
        - Josh and Jake routine
        - Jake: [break]
        - Paul Warren - cattle call
        - "Old MacDonald"
        - "Crying Holy Unto The Lord"
        - "What A Friend We Have In Jesus"
          Paul Warren, fiddle
        - "Cabin On The Hill"
        - "Wildwood Flower"
        - "If I Should Wander Back Tonight"
        - "Blackberry Blossom"
        - "Barnyard"
          (Hot Corn, Cold Corn)
        - song by Curly Secker
        - "Sally Ann"
        - Marth White Flour coupon distribution
        - "Shuckin' The Corn"
  - Early bluegrass singles dubs, AFC 2002/009: SR202; Herb Trotman; 1 sound tape reel (Track 1: 00:46:37, Track 2: 00:48:12, Track 3: 00:48:30, Track 4: 00:48:21): analog, 3 3/4 ips, quarter track, mono; 5 in.
    - Side 1, track 1 (left)
      - "My Ship Will Sail" - Rebe and Rabe with the Happy Valley Boys, 1951
        Tennessee 773 (3094)
      - "That Gloryland Mansion In The Sky" - Rebe and Rabe with the Happy Valley Boys, 1951
        Tennessee 773 (3093)
      - "You Broke Your Promise" - Lonesome Pine Fiddlers, 1952
        RCA Victor 20-4857 (E2VB-6241)
      - "Nobody Cares (Not Even You)" - Lonesome Pine Fiddlers, 1952
        RCA Victor 20-4857 (E2VB-6243)
      - "Dixie Medley" including "Arkansas Traveler" Sailor's Hornpipe" "Turkey In The Straw" - Fred Van Eps, 1923
        1011-A 735-3
      - "Kentucky Babe" - Stellar Quartette, 1923
        (LL4514-1) 1011-B
      - "Returned From Missing In Action" - Smilin' Jim Eanes and His Shenandoah Valley Boys, 1953
        Blue Ridge 201-A (1002)
      - "Long Journey Home" - Smilin' Jim Eanes and His Shenandoah Valley Boys, 1953
        Blue Ridge 201-B (7007)
      - "Drunken Highway" - Smilin' Jim Eanes and His Shenandoah Valley Boys, 1952
        Blue Ridge 301 (4402)
      - "A Sweeter Love Than Yours I'll Never Know" - Smilin' Jim Eanes and His Shenandoah Valley Boys, 1952
        Blue Ridge 301 (0033)
      - "You Better Wake Up" - Jim Eanes, 1949
        Capitol 57-40174 (4232)
      - "Baby Blue Eyes" - Jim Eanes, 1949
        Capitol 57-40174 (4044)
      - "Love and Wealth" - Carl Story and the Rambling Mountaineers, 1953
        Columbia 21137 (co 49488)
      - "Lonesome Hearted Blues" - Carl Story and the Rambling Mountaineers, 1953
        Columbia 21137 (co 49489)
      - "A Sweeter Love Than Yours I'll Never Know" - The Church Brothers and Their Blue Ridge Ramblers, 1951
        Rich-R-Tone 1009-B (1400)
      - "I Know My Name Will Be Called Up There" - The Church Brothers and Their Blue Ridge Ramblers, 1952
        Rich-R-Tone 1017 (1310)
      - "We'll Meet Up There" - The Church Brothers and Their Blue Ridge Ramblers, 1952
        Rich-R-Tone 1017 (1408)
      - "Tennessee Boy" - Frank Hunter and his Black Mountain Boys, 1952
        Rich-R-Tone 1049 (1349)
    - Side 2, left track
      - "Long Time No See" - Frank Hunter and his Black Mountain Boys, 1952
        Rich-R-Tone 1049 (1440); vocal duet by Frank Hunter and Gene Christian
      - "Throwing Water On The Flame" - Jack and Daniel and the Sourwood Mountain Boys, 1952
        Decca 28207 (82591)
      - "All Hope Is Gone" - Jack and Daniel and the Sourwood Mountain Boys, 1952
        Decca 28207 (82594)
      - "Sold Down The River" - The Blue Sky Boys, 1947
        RCA Victor 20-2380
      - "I'm Glad (I'm Glad He's Gone And Left You)" - The Blue Sky Boys, 1947
      - "My Blue Eyed Boy" - Martin and Roberts, 1932
        Conqueror 8146-B (11565)
      - "Do You Wander" - Tom Morgan and the Log Cabin Boys, undated
      - "The Old Man Sawin' and Pickin' On The Strings - Pete Roberts (fiddle), Bill Offenbacker (guitar), Buddy Davis (mandolin), undated
      - "Church Back Home" - Emerson, Duffey, Waller, T. Morgan, undated
      - "High Lonesome," undated
      - "Mother, Sweet Mother" - Rebe and Rabe, 1952
        Tennessee 836
      - "Land Of Eternal Peace" - Rebe and Rabe, 1952
      - "Hallelujah We Shall Rise" - Sauceman Brothers with Their Hillbilly Ramblers Quartet, 1950
      - "I'll Be No Stranger There" - Sauceman Brothers with Their Hillbilly Ramblers Quartet, 1950
      - "Stars In My Crown" - Buster Pack and His Lonesome Pine Boys, 1952
      - "In The Land Of Peace And Love" - Buster Pack and His Lonesome Pine Boys, 1952
      - "Dickson County Breakdown" - Stanley Brothers, 1954
        Mer 6106 (YB7531)
      - "I'll Never Make You Blue" - Frank Wakefield, 1965
        Silver Belle GS 451005
      - "The Convict And The Child" - Frank Wakefield, 1965
    - Side 1, track 2 (right)
      - "Ring Of Fire" - The Sand Mountain Playboys, 1965
        ChesCamp 102-A
      - "You Can Call Me Darling" - The Sand Mountain Playboys, 1965
        ChesCamp 102-B
      - Doc Hamilton's Barnyard Show and Fiddle Course, undated
        Archivist's note: no context for this entry in the documentation.
      - Doc Hamilton's tape about Texas fiddling, undated
      - Three multiple recordings by me
        - "Back Along The Road To Texas," undated
          "I wrote with three guitars"
    - Side 2 (right)
      - Three multiple recordings by me
        - "Dead Flowers," undated
          Rolling Stones song; two guitars, two voices
        - "New River Train," undated
          F-4, banjo, guitar, bass, two voices
      - "That Day Is Coming" - Carl Story and His Rambling Mountaineers, 1951
        Mer 6303 (7017-1)
      - "He Will Set Your Fields On Fire" - Carl Story and His Rambling Mountaineers, 1951
        Mer 6303 (7017-2)
      - "I'd Rather Be Alone" - Flatt and Scruggs, 1954
        Columbia 21248 (CO 49892)
      - "Someone Took My Place With You" - Flatt and Scruggs, 1954
        Columbia 21248 (CO 49894)
      - The Bailey Brothers (unconfirmed)
        Dub copy of a tape owned by Tom Morgan.
        - "Lonesome Road Blues," undated
        - "Rattlesnake Daddy Blues," 1949
        - "Alabama," 1949
        - "The Sweetest Gift, A Mother's Smile," 1949
        - "John Henry," 1950
        - "I Will Never Marry," 1950
      - Pee Wee Lambert and Curly Parker
        - "Weary Hobo," 1952
        - "Just A Memory," 1952
      - Jim Eanes and the Shenandoah Valley Boys
        - "Blue Yodel #1," 1958
        - "Florida Blues," 1958
        - "I Took Her By Her Little Brown Hand," 1952
        - "I'll Never Ever Love You Anymore," 1952
  - "Midnight Special" (radio program), KPFA; Janet Smith and Tom Barton at The Berkeley; Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Berkeley; Janet Smith (solo) at The Berkeley; Neil Rosenberg at The Berkeley; Lorain County String Band, Oberlin, AFC 2002/009: SR203; Tom Barton
    - Sound recording, RXI 0174; 1 sound tape reel: analog, 7 1/2 ips, left quarter-track, mono; 7 in.
      - Side 1
        - Midnight Special (radio program), KPFA, July 25, 1959
          - "How Mountain Girls Can Love" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers
            Personnel: Pete Berg, guitar; Scott Hambly, mandolin; Neil Rosenberg, banjo
          - "Little Maggie" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers
          - "The Gypsie's Garden" - Janet Smith and Tom Barton
          - "Salty Dog" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers
          - "New River Train"- Redwood Canyon Ramblers
          - "Reuben" - Redwood Canyon Ramblers
          - "Amelia Earhart" - Scott Hambly
          - "Jimmy Brown" - parody by Pete Berg
        - Janet Smith and Tom Barton, Berkeley, circa July 30, 1959
          - "Hand Me Down My Walking Cane"
        - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Berkeley Hillel, July 25, 1959
          Personnel: Pete Berg, Scott Hambly, and Neil Rosenberg
          - "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms"
          - "Salty Dog"
          - "Reuben"
          - "Red Rocking Chair"
          - "Dim Lights, Thick Smoke"
        - Janet Smith, Berkeley, circa July 30, 1959
          - "Down By The Greenwood Sidey-O"
      - Side 2
        - Neil Rosenberg, Berkeley, July 30, 1959
          - "John Johanna"
          - "Titanic"
          - "Railroad Bill"
          - "God Loves His Children"
        - Lorain County String Band, Oberlin
          See SR016 for personnel. All cuts are on that tape except "Train 45." for which the personnel are the same as"Ruben's Train," except Frank plays regular guitar. Demo recorded at WOBC, Oberlin, Ohio.
          - "Lorain County Breakdown," May 31, 1959
            Also known as "Big Tilda"
          - "Pike County Breakdown," May 16, 1959
          - "Death Of McKinley," May 31, 1959
            Also known as "White House Blues"
          - "Ruben's Train," May 31, 1959
          - "Train 45," May 16, 1959
          - "Romie," May 16, 1959
          - "Pike County Breakdown," May 16, 1959
            Same as previous
        - Neil Rosenberg, Berkeley
          - John Henry, July 30, 1959
    - Documentation
      - Song list and production notes for SR203, July 4, 2011, rcr1959-07-25.txt; 1 manuscript; black and white, digital (.txt)
      - Handwritten set list, undated, rcr1959-07-25.pdf; 1 manuscript; color, digital (.pdf)
      - Back of the tape box, with handwritten notes, undated, rcr1959-07-25_26tapebox.pdf; 1 manuscript; color, digital (.pdf)